Magic. Mystery. Marmalade.
Paddington 2 is a adventure, comedy, family film directed by Paul King.
Paddington, now happily settled with the Browns, picks up a series of odd jobs
to buy the perfect present for his Aunt Lucy, but it is stolen.
Paddington Brown (voice), played by Ben Whishaw.
Mary Brown, played by Sally Hawkins.
Henry Brown, played by Hugh Bonneville.
Judy Brown, played by Madeleine Harris.
Jonathan Brown, played by Samuel Joslin.
Mrs. Bird, played by Julie Walters.
Paddington 2 is a 2017 live-action animated comedy film directed by Paul King and written by King and Simon Farnaby, based on the
stories of Paddington Bear, created by Michael Bond (to whom the film is also dedicated, Bond having died that year).
It is the second in the Paddington film series.
The film, a British-French-Luxembourgish co-production, stars Ben Whishaw as the voice of Paddington, with Hugh Bonneville,
Sally Hawkins, Brendan Gleeson, Julie Walters, Jim Broadbent, Peter Capaldi and Hugh Grant in live-action roles.
In the film, after Paddington is framed and imprisoned for a burglary that he did not
commit, he and his family have to find the real culprit and prove his innocence.
The film was confirmed to be in development in April 2015.
Principal photography began in October 2016 and ended in June 2017.
The film was theatrically released on 10 November 2017 in the United
Kingdom and on 6 December in France, and grossed $290 million.
Paddington 2 received critical acclaim and was nominated for three BAFTAs: Outstanding
British Film, Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actor, for Grant.
A third film, Paddington in Peru, was released in 2024.
The film explores themes of london, england, based on
novel or book, sequel, bear, train.
The tone is lighthearted.